Chrysostomos Bakouras

Software Engineer

Phone: +30 6949293080

Address: Trapezountos 22, Stavroupoli,
Thessaloniki, Greece

Email: chbakouras@gmail.com

Experienced 4+ years Software Engineer with strong problem-solving skills. Specialize in thinking outside the box to find unique solutions to difficult engineering problems. Proficient at designing software and writing code in various languages. Expert in Java. Enthusiastic team player and deep creative thinker.

Experience

DataScouting

DECEMBER 2015 - JUNE 2016

Internship

- Implement a microservice for pdf concatenation with Spring Boot and PDFtk.
- Implement a microservice for delivery and schedule of email alerts with Spring Boot. Email alerts contained media monitoring reports targeted to customer needs.
- Create a module in MediaScouting Broadcast, for mass import of advertisement creatives.
- Refactor DataScouting sites (www.datascouting.com and blog.datascouting.com) to be compatible with Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.0 and W3C specification.
- Refactor internationalization system in MediaScouting Print. (Java ee, Gxt/Gwt)

DataScouting

JUNE 2016 - PRESENT

Software Engineer

- Implement a microservice for product / company / brands / creatives catalog management. One of the key concepts of this project was to replicate data among multiple database schemas. Technologies used: Spring boot, Atomikos, JTA, JPA, Hibernate.
- Implement Ad Monitoring platform inside MediaScouting Print. Technologies used GWT/GXT Java ee.
- Refactor MediaScouting Print. Change dependency management and build system from Ant to Maven. Refactor most of project modules to MVP design. Redesign Curation module and Admin module.
- I was a member of the team which developed the MediaScouting Print API microservice. This microservice is responsible for Customer Article/Clip auto matching, fuzzy searching articles with Elasticsearch and ZomboDB and exposes most of the domain layer of MediaScouting Print.
- Implement a mailing microservice responsible for external company mails. Technologies used Spring Boot, Java Mailer and Mailgun API.
- Implement automatic customer alerts microservice. This Microservice is responsible for data collecting for each customer and send reports with a desired way (webhook, email, ftp).
- Implement a microservice for serving resources (images, video, audio). One of the key concepts was to allow the resource to be opened one time or until a date.

- Refactor MediaScouting Broadcast Audiofingerprinting Microservice, Facedetection Microservice and LogoDetection. Expose Rest APIs build with Spring Boot.
- Implement Audiofingerprinting SDK, FaceDetection SDK and LogoDetection SDK.
- Refactor MediaScouting Broadcast Grabber.
- Implement MediaScouting Broadcast Grabber health reporting API.
- Implement licensing for all company products.
- Implement Mention SDK and mention syncer microservice.

FastClick Ltd

SEPTEMBER 2015 - PRESENT

Software Engineer

- Implement an e-commerce Admin Panel for customer / order / campaign management. Technologies used: PHP 5.6, Laravel.
- Implement a rule based web scraper for internet articles integrated with Wordpress cms. Technologies used: PHP 5.6, Laravel, ElasticSearch.
- Implement Customer gateway API for orders and site widgets. Technologies used: PHP 5.6, Laravel.
- Integrate Admin Panel with paypal.
- Integrate Admin Panel with Routee API. Create a SMS validation system for order verification.
- Implement a drag and drop template designing tool for product landing pages.
- Implement a Classified Ads platform. Technologies used: PHP 7, Laravel, ElasticSearch.
- Implement an url shortener containing link monitoring and user analytics functionalities. Technologies: Node.js, Restify.
- Implement Bot API. A Node.js backend for facebook bot building and customer management.
- Implement Bot Admin. An Angular 5 app that uses Bot Api for bot building and customer management.

Education

Technological Educational Institute of Central Macedonia

2009 - PRESENT

Pending Graduates' oath

Information and Communications Technology

University of Cambridge

First Certificate in Computing

University of Michigan

Certificate of Competency in English

Skills

- Object Oriented Programming
- Functional Programming
- Java, Java ee
- GWT/GXT
- Spring Framework, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Spring Security
- JTA, Atomikos
- JPA, Hibernate
- Thymeleaf
- Vavr / Javaslang
- RabitMQ
- Maven, Gradle, Ant
- Kotlin, Groovy
- JavaScript, ECMAScript 5, ECMAScript 6, Flow
- Angular 5
- Node.js
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, zombodb, Elasticsearch, Redis
- Gii
- PHP, Laravel
- Zookeeper
- Linux